Vikramjeet Sangavkar

LEAD PERFORMANCE ENGINEER

PROFILE

Working as Performance Engineer with 11 years of relevant experience. Passionate in diving into large complex enterprise systems to get them work well in production reliably scalable and efficient. Excellent team player and strong analytical skills

CONTACT



sangavkar.vikramjeet@gmail.com



9255968942



vickys31.github.io/resume



<u>vikramjeetsangavkar</u>



Pleasanton, California

SKILLS

Non-functional requirements
Cloud Performance Optimization
Heap & JVM Analysis
Database Tuning & Profiling
Workload modelling
Linux & Windows Monitoring
Load Test Automation
Programming knowledge

Performance & Scalability Engineering RCA, Code tuning and profiling

Mobile & IVR Performance validation

Monolithic & Microservices Scalability

ACHIEVEMENTS

NFT Testrix - 1st Runner up Cognizant QE&A- 2019

A-Team Award - Client Recognition Cognizant Barclays - 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Performance Analyst

COGNIZANT

2017-Present

- Involved in Capacity planning, Performance assessment, Business/Material Impact Analysis
- Ownership of E2E Performance Engineering activities supporting both Agile and Waterfall/Release based programs.
- Developing scripts using JMeter, LoadRunner and NeoLoad using popular protocols.
- Generate/monitor: Load, stress, Endurance test using leading APM tools like Dynatrace, AppDynamics, Wily Introscope and SiteScope.
- Extensive thread and heap analysis for performance issue troubleshooting. Also involved in code quality optimizations.
- Owning Performance Bottlenecks analyzing both client and server-side statistics is conducted and detailed reports are shared with development team.
- Emulated IVR calls and replicated customer operations using Cyara and Hammer DTMF logs, interact with an interactive voice menu, and measure line quality.

Senior Performance Engineer

SYNECHRON

2013-2017

- Gathering Non-Functional Requirements with Business Team and Development team.
- Designing Performance Test Strategy based on application architecture and work load model.
- Conducting Performance Impact Analysis before each release.
- Environment set up monitoring tools for performance testing activities and associated dashboards.
- Developing scripts using JMeter and LoadRunner using various protocols.
- Generate/monitor: Load, spike, stress, Endurance test using leading APM tools like Dynatrace and SiteScope.
- Supported DB optimizations by showcasing AWR analysis skills to conjugate with application server and capacity demand.

Performance Engineer

ACCENTURE

2009-2013

- Build a repository of historical test results and analysis for analyzing trends over a time.
- Designing Performance Test plan based on scope.
- Conducting Performance Impact Analysis before each release.
- Environment set up monitoring tools for performance testing activities and associated dashboards.
- Developing scripts using LoadRunner using HTTP and RTE protocols.
- Generate/monitor: Load, stress, Endurance test using leading APM tools like Dynatrace.
- Creating Script (Recording and enhancing/debugging of script using Vugen) as per requirement and followed the performance testing process.
- Created 2 tools: for report Performance Test Execution Report generation (using Excel macros) and one GUI based tool for converting text from PDF to XML file (developed using PERL) which was used by the functional team which reduced their testing efforts by 70%.

EDUCATION

Master in Computer Applications

UNIVERSITY OF PUNE

2006-2009

 Bachelor of Computer Science SHIVAJI UNIVERSITY

2003-2006